VICTOR FAJARDO

13297C Blueberry Ln #202, Fairfax, VA 22033 | 703-459-7611 | fajardo.de.leon@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/victorfajardo | github.com/VictorFajardo

Self-Taught Software Engineer

Worked over 2 decades in software development using latest technologies to build user-friendly products for companies in America, and Europe for international brands like Coca-Cola, Nestlé, Beiersdorf, Nextel, Kimberly-Clark, among others.

Review some of my previous projects <a href="https://example.com/here-build-next-align: left-build-next-align: left-build-next

Skills

Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban Development: OOP, MVC, MVVC DevOps: AWS CI / CD Languages: HTML5, XHTML, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Java, Python, ActionScript3

Frameworks: React, Gatsby, Next, Angular, NodeJS, Express, Webpack, Code Igniter

APIs: RESTful APIs, GraphQL, Apollo, Google, Twitter, Epsilon, Brightcove, Hubspot, Mailchimp

Libraries: jQuery, Redux, Webpack, WebGL, ESLint, Prettier, GreenSock, GSAP, Bootstrap, Material Design, Lodash,

TailwindCSS, Styled-Components, Scroll Magic, Three.js, Axios

Databases: SQL, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Cloud DB's **Test-Driven Tools:** Jest, Enzyme **Version Control:** Git, GitHub, BitBucket **Servers:** Apache, AWS EC2 / S3, Firebase Auth / DB

Software: Adobe CC Suite, SketchUp, Microsoft Office Suite, Postman, Bitvise

Spoken Languages: English, Spanish (Native)

Work Experience

Senior Lead Full-Stack Developer, Jul 2019 to Jun 2022 – <u>WUNDERMAN THOMPSON</u>, Washington, DC Lead developer, defining data architecture, designing, developing, testing, deploying, and maintaining several high-traffic responsive websites, interactive experiences, rich media banners and user medical tools for pharmaceutical companies like Pfizer, Merck, Johnson & Johnson, Boehringer Ingelheim, Kaiser Permanente, among others. Worked in a fast-paced work environment delivering cutting-edge technology products using modern frameworks like TypeScript, React, Redux, Node.js and Express, with a pixel-perfect level of detail and commitment.

Achievement Highlights:

- Received the "Matt Reese Employee of The Year Award" for innovation, excellence, and leadership.
- Contributed software engineering expertise in the planning process of products and services through the software lifecycle.
- Assumed the leadership and management of the development department (frontend and backend teams) as interim director after the departure of our former director.
- Assigned task and projects to developers based on abilities and experience. Cultivated a one-to-one professional
 relationship with team members to help them to grow professionally.
- Participated in client meetings translating technical issues into easy-to-understand solutions, achieving agreements with clients based on cost-benefit decision making.

Senior Web Developer, Dec 2016 to Jul 2019 – <u>WUNDERMAN THOMPSON</u>, Washington, DC *Achievement Highlights:*

- Mentored entry and mid-level developers, preparing them to take an active participation of the development of the department projects. Trained new department members to integrate them to our development process.
- Facilitated customization of systems by encouraging development team to adopt high level standards for software application development, architecture, continuous deployment, innovative frameworks, modern IDEs, and tools.
- Interviewed candidates to the department based on the demands of the position and the incoming projects to be developed.

Web Developer, Nov 2014 to Dec 2016 – <u>WUNDERMAN THOMPSON</u>, Washington, DC *Achievement Highlights:*

• Introduced methodologies and best practices that enhanced product definition, release processes and customization of applications to client needs creating products of undemanding scalability and facile maintenance.

 Created quality standards for the development of banners and rich media banners that were later adopted by other branches of the company. Contributed with my experience in the process of conceptualization and brainstorming of banner campaigns.

Software Developer, Mar 2008 to Sep 2014 - Multiple Advertising Agencies

Web Developer / Content Creator, Jun 1996 to Jul 2003 – <u>YUPI / CIUDAD FUTURA</u>, Miami, FL / Madrid, Spain Developed content related to Video Games: Articles, News, Tools, and Guides, among others.

Education

2023 - Northern Virginia Community College – Annandale, VA (Computer Science – AS)Undergraduate. Completed courses: Computer Science, University Math, University Physics. GPA: 4.0

Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

2005 - Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos – Lima, Peru (Electronic Engineering – BE) Undergraduate. Completed courses: University Math, University Physics.

Last Side Projects

- Employee Feedback App Typescript React Redux Toolkit Firebase Auth / Database Material UI ESLint
- Tweet Feed Kiosk Typescript React Redux Toolkit NodeJS Express Styled-Components Axios Lodash
- Metaverse Project Typescript React Redux Toolkit ThreeJS WebGL

Last Work Projects

- Pfizer 3D Discovery Center React Redux Typescript Three.js Material Design Bootstrap 4 Brightcove API
- <u>Exploring Kaiser Permanent</u> React Redux Typescript Three.js Material Design Bootstrap 4
- Understanding ILD Progression Angular 8 Typescript Custom-Made Animation Engine Bootstrap 4
- Lungs & You® PHP Angular REST APIs Google Maps API Brightcove API
- OFEV® PHP Angular REST APIs Brightcove API